{"tossups": [{}, {"question": "5 million Mexican immigrants. The man\u2019s New Look policy, developed with his Secretary of State, John Foster Dulles, involved a policy of \u201cmassive retaliation\u201d with nuclear weapons in the event of an attack. His namesake Highway Act was inspired by the Autobahn during his time in Germany. For the point, name this Supreme Commander of Allied Forces during World War II and 34th U.S. President.", "answer": "Dwight D.<b> Eisenhower</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "The southern end of the Tihamah lies in this country, which disputes the Hanish Islands with Eritrea. The Mahrah Sultanate governed in this modern day country, which includes the island of Socotra. In 2000 in this nation, a small explosives-laden boat detonated itself next to a refueling U.S. destroyer. This country\u2019s current civil war involves a Shia-led Houthi insurgency. For the point, name this Arabian Peninsula country whose capital is Sana and whose port city of Aden was the site of the USS<em> Cole</em> bombing.", "answer": "<b> Yemen</b>", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {}, {}, {"question": "This artist was inspired by the Belvedere Torso to create a print where a mutilated naked man sits on top of a tree stump. He created a series that included \u201cemphatic caprices\u201d and \u201cfatal consequences\u201d of a war with France. This artist depicted events from the Peninsular War in<em> The Charge of the Mamelukes</em> and a work in which a man in a white shirt stretches his arms upward in front of a firing squad. For the point, name this Spanish artist of the \u201cDisasters of War\u201d prints and<em> The Third of May, 1808</em>.", "answer": "Francisco<b> Goya</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {"question": "The rule of this family is the primary subject of the Chronicle of Fredegar. One ruler from this family was baptized by Saint Remigius; that ruler was also the first to implement Salic law. The Alemanni were defeated by the forces of this dynasty at the Battle of Tolbiac by King Clovis I. The last ruler of this dynasty was overthrown by Mayor of the Palace Pepin the Short. For the point, name this Frankish dynasty that was succeeded by the Carolingians.", "answer": "<b> Merovingian</b> Dynasty", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "One of events ended with the caning of a man carrying two malfunctioning pistols. Another of these events took place at the Blair House and was carried out by Puerto Rican pro-independence activists. Within two weeks in September 1975, Lynette Fromme and Sara Jane Moore each carried out one of these events. The subject of another of these events quipped \u201cI hope you\u2019re all Republicans\u201d to his operating team. Gerald Ford was twice targeted by, for the point, what type of event, which John Hinckley carried out in March 1981 against Ronald Reagan?", "answer": "<b> unsuccessful assassination</b>s of (or<b> assassination attempts</b> on) U.S.<b> President</b>s (do not prompt on \u201cassassinations of U.S. Presidents\u201d)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "One of these documents claims to lay the foundation of a government of \u201cmen for men\u201d, rather than \u201cangels\u201d for men. Robert Yates opposed these documents in a similarly titled set of opposing documents written under the pseudonym of \u201cBrutus.\u201d William Duer wrote a series of essays defending these documents under the name of \u201cFriend of Publius,\u201d the pseudonymous author of these documents. The spread of factions in democracy is warned against in the tenth entry of, for the point, what set of 85 essays, written by Hamilton, Jay, and Madison, to promote the U.S. Constitution?", "answer": "The<b> Federalist</b> Papers", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Two answers required. A festival honoring these two figures required all wives of Greek citizens to attend, involved the sacrifice of pigs, and was known as the Thesmophoria. These two figures were the subject of a cult whose initiation rituals were the Eleusinian [ell-ooh-SIN-ian] Mysteries. The change of seasons in Ancient Greece was attributed to the annual separation of these figures, as the younger was forced to spend the winter with Hades. For the point, name this pair, consisting of the Greek goddess of agriculture and her daughter.", "answer": "<b> Demeter</b> and<b> Persephone</b> (prompt if only one given) Page 2", "metadata": "Mythology - Mythology"}, {"question": "In 2015, after two years, this group announced the death of its leader. This group carried out the destruction of various Buddha statues at Bamiyan and was ousted from power after a NATO coalition force invaded in 2001. For the point, name this terrorist group whose insurgents seek to regain control of Afghanistan.", "answer": "<b> Taliban</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "For the point, name this country once ruled by Nicolae Ceausescu [chow-shess-koo] from Bucharest.", "answer": "<b> Romania</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "Atlee Pomerene and Owen Roberts led a bipartisan investigation into this event. The Supreme Court affirmed the Congressional power to compel testimony in a response to Mally Daugherty, whose brother, Attorney General Harry Daugherty, refused to investigate this event. Edward Doheny was given access to Elk Hills after providing a no-interest loan to the Secretary of the Interior. Albert Fall received bribes in return for oil drilling leases on federal land in, for the point, what scandal that rocked the Warren G. Harding administration?", "answer": "<b> Teapot Dome</b> scandal", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This composer collected 150 late pieces in his<em> Sins of Old Age</em>, and depicted a legendary Babylonian queen in his opera<em> Semiramide</em>. One of his pieces, which Berlioz described as a \u201csymphony in four parts\u201d, contains the \u201crans des vaches\u201d [rahn day VAHSH] and ends with a galop. That piece is derived from an opera by this composer in which Gessler forces the title Swiss patriot to shoot an apple off Jemmy\u2019s head. For the point, name this composer who wrote an oft-quoted overture for his final opera,<em> William Tell</em>.", "answer": "Gioachino<b> Rossini</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Auditory Fine Arts"}, {"question": "This man\u2019s mausoleum is rumored to be buried near the \u201cLost City of the Giants\u201d in Llanganates [yan-gan-ah-tays] National Park. This leader won a civil war at the Battle of Quipaipan, but 5,000 of his forces were ambushed and defeated at Cajamarca [ka-ha-mar-kah]. After the death of this man\u2019s father, Huayna Capac, he defeated and imprisoned his brother Huascar. This man requested to be strangled instead of burned at the stake by Francisco Pizarro. For the point, name this last sovereign ruler of the Incas.", "answer": "<b> Atahualpa</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "This city\u2019s police department was once led by Daryl Gates. The killing of three-year-old Stephanie Kuhen in this city led to three convictions in the \u201cWrong Way\u201d murder trial. In 1992, Curtis Yarbrough rescued Reginald Denny at the intersection of Florence and Normandie Avenues in this city; that attack occurred during a riot triggered by a not guilty verdict for excessive force by police against Rodney King. The Watts Riots occurred in, for the point, what most populous city in southern California?", "answer": "<b> L</b>os<b> A</b>ngeles, California Page 4", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "The Society of Cincinnati was formed in honor of this President, who sent Charles Pinckney to sign a treaty that allowed for navigation rights on the Mississippi River. This man issued the Proclamation of Neutrality in response to Citizen Genet\u2019s actions to recruit supporters for foreign wars, and he warned of the formation of political parties and \u201centangling alliances\u201d in his farewell address. For the point, name this president who led the Continental Army during the American Revolution.", "answer": "George<b> Washington</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Alfonso X of Castille described variants of this activity \u201cof the four seasons\u201d and an \u201castronomical\u201dvariant in the first section of his<em> Book of Games</em>. Soviet domination at this activity during the Cold War began with the success of Mikhail Botvinnik, while the only American World Champion at this activity before the fall of the USSR later got his citizenship revoked due to anti-Semitic comments and lived as a recluse in Iceland. For the point, name this board game whose famous players include Deep Blue, Garry Kasparov, and Bobby Fischer.", "answer": "<b> chess</b>", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {"question": "Louis Bl\u00b4eriot was the first man to fly across this body of water. A World War I mine & net blockade of this body of water, named the \u201cBarrage\u201d of one city on its shores, was briefly rendered ineffective when German submarines simply crossed on the surface at night. The port cities of Dieppe and Calais [ca-LAY] lie on this body of water, which was crossed by over one hundred thousand soldiers on June 6, 1944. The Cliffs of Dover overlook, for the point, what body of water between France and England?", "answer": "<b> English Channel</b>", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {"question": "This man asked \u201cWhy, then, are we not simply Marxists?\u201d in his work<em> Search for a Method</em>. This man wrote that to shoot down a European is \u201cto kill two birds with one stone\u201d in his introduction to Frantz Fanon\u2019s<em> The Wretched of the Earth</em>. This man stated that \u201cexistence precedes essence\u201d in a lecture about how the title concept \u201cis a humanism.\u201d This man uses the example of a caf\u00b4e waiter\u2019s duties as a form of \u201cbad faith\u201d in his work<em> Being and Nothingness</em>. For the point, name this French existentialist philosopher.", "answer": "Jean-Paul<b> Sartre</b>", "metadata": "Philosophy - Philosophy"}, {"question": "This city removed its Embarcadero Freeway after a disaster near Loma Prieta. This city\u2019s artificial Treasure Island is connected via causeway to Yerba Buena Island. A former military base in this city, the Presidio, contains the southern approach for an iconic orange suspension bridge. For the point, name this city on the northern San Andreas Fault, which suffered a 1906 earthquake and contains the Golden Gate Bridge.", "answer": "<b> San Francisco</b>, California", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "The dampened, corned type of this substance was a 14th century improvement on the dry, ground serpentine type. Taoist alchemists accidentally invented this substance when trying to come up with an elixir of immortality. This substance\u2019s original form was a mixture of saltpeter, sulfur, and carbon. Due to the production of different solid by-products, this substance was gradually replaced by smokeless varieties. For the point, name this substance used to shoot bullets out of firearms.", "answer": "<b> gunpowder</b> or<b> black powder</b> (prompt on \u201cexplosive\u201d) <b>Extra Question</b> Only read if moderator botches a question.", "metadata": "Science - Chemistry"}, {"question": "This president signed the Mongrel Tariff, and Congress overrode his veto of the Rivers and Harbors Act. This president signed another act which initially mandated that ten percent of federal jobs be filled by examination, despite his history as a Stalwart in Roscoe Conkling\u2019s patronage system. The Pendleton Civil Service Reform Act was signed by, for the point, what man who became President after the assassination of James Garfield?", "answer": "Chester Alan<b> Arthur</b> Page 6", "metadata": "History - American History"}], "bonuses": []}